AMAL NASIR ALMANSOUR

<u>almansouramal@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/amal-almansour/ https://github.com/Amal-Nasir Chicago, IL +1 4803885022

OBJECTIVE

Passionate and results-driven Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science focusing on medical informatics, computer vision, data science, and machine learning. Seeking a full-time position as a Computer Vision Engineer, Data Scientist, Data Engineer, or Machine Learning Engineer, leveraging strong research and software engineering skills.

RESEARCH

My research lies at the intersection of ML/AI, CV, and health enhancement engineering at the Visual Informatics and Data Analytics [VIDA] lab, at DePaul University, focusing on quantifying label uncertainty and model uncertainty using image data. Collaborated with Dr. Jacob Furst and Daniela Raicu, exploring novel approaches to learn the limitations of learning in the presence of uncertainty within human agreement.

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Computer Science, DePaul University, Chicago, IL - September 2019-Expected Summer 2024 - GPA 3.98/4.00 Master of Science, Computer Science, California State University, Fullerton, CA - May 2016 - GPA 3.86/4.00 Bachelor of Science, Information Technology, King Saud University, Saudi Arabia - June 2011 - GPA 4.06/5.00

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python, R, Java, iOS (Swift)
- Machine learning: TensorFlow, PyTorch, scikit-learn, MLOps tools (MLflow) and many other ML algorithms and models such as clustering analysis, neural networks, VAE, GANs etc.
- Python IDEs: Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, Spyder, Jupyter Lab, Jupyter Notebook, IDLE, Sublime, Atom.
- Web Programming: PHP, HTML, and CSS
- Database Systems: Oracle, SQL and no SQL Databases, SAP HANA

EXPERIENCES

(2023) Data Scientist Intern at HERE Technologies ,

• Worked with the Lidar SLI extraction team, applying my data science and software engineering skills to a research effort focused on exploring practical methods to enhance model and pipeline-level classification accuracy for map automation.

(2021-2023) Graduate Assistant at DePaul University,

- Worked as a computer and data science tutor at the College of Computing and Digital Media.
- Worked as a grader for data science courses.

(2019-2021) Student Researcher at WHEEL Lab DePaul University 🧶,

- Served as the coordinator of the Wellness Health Enhancement Engineering (WHEEL) lab.
- Collected relevant data from the primary care project.
- Mentored and trained students to access the data and use the lab's software.
- Responsible for adding/removing students to/from IRB protocols.

(2018) Freelance iOS Mobile Developer,

• Worked remotely with startup companies, as an iOS mobile developer.

(2017) "SAP's Young Professional Program" ,

- SAP Certified Technology Associate SAP HANA (Edition 2016)
- Application Associate Business Intelligence with SAP BW 7.4 and SAP BI 4.1

VOLUNTEERING

(2021) Student volunteer at the ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST) conference,

- Organized paper sessions on Zoom.
- Helped with technical issues at the conference.

(2017-2018) Organizer volunteer with Women Who Code Chicago,

• Served as an organizer member of Women Who Code Chicago, particularly in the Machine Learning Focus group, for educating and supporting women in technology by organizing meetups and industry showcases.

(2016) iOS (swift) tutor,

• Help students build their apps, fix the issues, and make them understand basic algorithms.

LANGUAGES English, Arabic, Turkish